<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Lex Romo</title>
    <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lex Romo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 23:15:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lexromo.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Phishing Text Experience</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/blogs/phishingtext/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/blogs/phishingtext/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, gather around for a cautionary tale from the digital frontier. Today, I want to share a recent experience that left me both startled and enlightened about the dangers lurking in the depths of our mobile devices: a job offer text phishing scam.
Imagine this: I&amp;rsquo;m going about my day, minding my own business as usuall, when suddenly, my phone buzzes with an incoming text message. Expecting it to be yet another notification from a friend or a reminder about an upcoming appointment, I casually glance at the screen, only to be met with a message that sends my heart racing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Cyber Security Architecture Framework Experience</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects6/</guid>
      <description>As I moved from an intern to a permanent role at my workplace, I was excited about the opportunity to contribute in a more significant way. Yet, as I settled into my new position, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but notice a glaring gap in our organization&amp;rsquo;s defenses: the lack of a structured cybersecurity architecture. Having studied cybersecurity intensively during my time at university, I understood the critical importance of addressing this issue to protect our digital assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Hard drive to install another OS</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/harddrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/harddrive/</guid>
      <description>Split hard drive to install linux: Splitting a hard drive to install Linux refers to the process of dividing the storage space on a physical hard drive into multiple partitions or sections, with the intention of dedicating one or more of these partitions specifically for installing a Linux operating system.
When you split a hard drive to install Linux, you typically allocate a portion of the disk space to be used exclusively by the Linux operating system, its associated files, and possibly additional partitions for purposes like swap space or separate home directories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity and your digital print on the internet.</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/blogs/extra-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/blogs/extra-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Insights from the Podcast: &amp;ldquo;Teen Crypto Swappers: The Dark Web&amp;rsquo;s Rising Stars&amp;rdquo;: Hey everyone, I stumbled upon this fascinating podcast titled &amp;ldquo;These Teen Crypto Swappers Can Make $100,000 in 10 Mins - If They Don&amp;rsquo;t Get Caught🎙Ep 112 Dirty Coms&amp;rdquo; by Jack Rhysider, and let me tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s a real eye-opener.
Podcast summary: So, in this podcast, we get to hear from a guy they call &amp;ldquo;Drew,&amp;rdquo; although that&amp;rsquo;s not his real name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encryption and Decryption Python Script</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects3/</guid>
      <description>Encryption and Decryption Python Script: I wanted to share with you the project I recently completed for our university course, which involved creating a Python script for encryption and decryption. This project was a fascinating exploration into the world of cryptography and programming, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to tell you more about it.
First and foremost, cryptography plays a crucial role in securing sensitive information in today&amp;rsquo;s digital age. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s protecting personal communications, securing financial transactions, or safeguarding sensitive data, encryption serves as a vital tool for ensuring confidentiality and privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phishing Attack (Cybersecurity class final project)</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects2/</guid>
      <description>DO NOT USE THIS TOOL FOR MALICIOUS PURPOSES! Phishing is a form of cybercrime that involves attempting to acquire sensitive information, such as usernames, passwords, and credit card details, by posing as a trustworthy entity in electronic communication.
Engaging in such activities is against the law and violates ethical standards. It&amp;rsquo;s important to use your cybersecurity knowledge and skills to protect and secure systems, data, and individuals from cyber threats, rather than using them for malicious purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rootuser MFA Budget IAM</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/how-to-master-streamlit-for-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/how-to-master-streamlit-for-data-science/</guid>
      <description>AWS Here I create a Root user, I activated MFA to enhance the security of our AWS account. I activated the IAM because by default it is deactivated, and finally I activated and created a budget, so AWS can let us know when we are reaching our max budget.
In Amazon Web Services (AWS): The &amp;ldquo;root user&amp;rdquo; refers to the initial administrative user account created when you first set up an AWS account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/doc/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/doc/test/</guid>
      <description>Test page page </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog2</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/blogs/how-to-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/blogs/how-to-master/</guid>
      <description>Read blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure your .bashcr file in Linux</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects4/</guid>
      <description>.bashrc: As a Linux enthusiast, you understand the power of customization in optimizing your workflow and enhancing productivity. At the heart of this customization lies the .bashrc file, a versatile tool I like to use that allows you to tailor your command line environment to suit your needs.
By configuring your .bashrc file, you can create shortcuts and aliases for frequently used commands, enabling swift navigation and execution of tasks. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s accessing commonly used directories, launching preferred applications, or automating routine processes, these shortcuts can save valuable time and keystrokes in your daily interactions with the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IAM User Access Keys CLI</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects1/</guid>
      <description>AWS In Amazon Web Services (AWS): IAM (Identity and Access Management): IAM is a service that helps you securely control access to resources in your cloud environment. In the context of AWS (Amazon Web Services), IAM allows you to manage users, groups, and permissions to access AWS resources. Here are some key components of IAM:
Users: IAM users are entities that you create in AWS to represent the people and services that interact with AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More about me</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Greetings👋​, tech enthusiasts 🧑‍💻​👨‍💻​👩‍💻​, and welcome to the hub of all things innovative and cutting-edge🌐​! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have you join our community at my blog. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned IT professional, a curious tech novice, or someone who simply would like to see what I am up to welcome!
More about me:
I am Alex Romo👨‍💻​, better know as Lex Romo👦​. I have cultivated a deep fascination for the intricate realms of technology, finding a special passion in the fields of cybersecurity and cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3</title>
      <link>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexromo.net/blog/projects/projects5/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
